<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-28T09:33:50-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">watsonthedev</title><subtitle>A repository for my thoughts on programming</subtitle><entry><title type="html">15 Principles of Dev Management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/30/softwaremanager.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="15 Principles of Dev Management" /><published>2020-01-30T20:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-30T20:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/30/softwaremanager</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/30/softwaremanager.html"><![CDATA[<p>1. Assume good intent.</p>

<p>2. Listen first and seek to understand.</p>

<p>3. Clear is kind: dialogue driven by respect and honesty leads to better outcomes.</p>

<p>4. Diverse people from diverse backgrounds create better products.</p>

<p>5. All people inherently strive to show up, do a good job, and be proud of their work.</p>

<p>6. I often don't have the answers; therefore, I elevate the voices of those on my team with subject matter expertise.</p>

<p>7. There are no easy solutions to complex problems, and most of the problems dev teams are trying to solve are complex.</p>

<p>8. The core tenants of the <a href="https://agilemanifesto.org">Agile Manifesto</a> and the <a href="https://agilemanifesto.org/principles.html">Agile Principles</a> are as applicable today as they were when first written over 20 years ago.</p>

<p>9. There are no “bad devs” but rather good devs in bad circumstances.</p>

<p>10. As a corollary to #9, I do not believe that devs should be labeled as “rockstars”, “ninjas”, “hardcore”, etc.</p>

<p>11. The hiring process should be humanizing and respectful.</p>

<p>12. People deserve to be not only compensated for their time but also respected as holistic individuals who exist outside the workspace.</p>

<p>13. A stable system requires periods of calm self-reflection; constant growth impedes sustainability.</p>

<p>14. Non-action can be a perfectly valid and active choice.</p>

<p>15. These tenets apply to myself as much as they do to those with whom I work.</p>

<p>16. Even seasoned pros occasionally code off-by-one bugs.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1. Assume good intent.]]></summary></entry></feed>